All...good afternoon or almost...everyone my name is mark...time with the
...group I run patterns and practices as well as a...spends a lot of time working...customers and
...asher applications and one of the borrowing
...your lives which unfortunately there's no refund policy on the talk a little bit about some of the
...with customers...experienced moments of rapid
and terrifying success and I've had some learning moments in that process share a little bit of the
...share little to the suffering and then talk about what the how things might have gone if we made a
few small choices just a little earlier in the process you seen that
slide already okay so essentially ...walk through the journey to scale a
lot about the process a lot about the questions a lot about the things that help you get ready for
being wildly successful in a website or services delivery without having to over engineer
over build up-front talking about systems that can
experience rapid growth or demand spikes and what are some of the things you can do to get ready for that?
Mostly architecture mostly design decisions
engineering tradeoffs what a lot of code in this one will be a lot of stories there will be intense
...of sarcasm education...of mockery of things I've done if that's a little overwhelming
...lots...a great sessions going on right now but other than that let's dive
...spend an hour together known ran out screaming cool all right.
So, we're not...talk a lot about features regardless of the technology stack you can pretty
much drop anything in here and the same set of physics and the same set of engineering choices apply
...really going to talk about the journey not the destination and the things you can do along
the way or mostly going to talk about scale...availability
being very inextricably tied together and how to leave the door open for successes
...over building some of the stories I'm going to tell their either slightly...or
details them blended together so as not to kind of give away
what really happened because we'll talk about the success stories but analyzer dirty laundry in public
right so this is a direct quote that showed up in my inbox...call it six months ago
wasn't six months but for the perspective, you know, for this talk let's go so today has been
a complete...I do not understand how website crash
immediately upon receiving traffic yes this was from a digital marketing agency so,
any idea why our website might crash immediately upon launch assuming that
is functionally correct and...past all unit testing?
Let's run some number shelley.
Thirty
five thousand requests per second in the first four minutes.
But, we go but this is asher we can build some big stuff on this platform where rock
stars.
Now let's take a little bit deeper.
I think okay I'm actually fairly glad we didn't have a
machine datacenter physically catch on fire.
Kudos to our...our build-out teams for you know, thinking a fire safety.
But, just the tap things off.
So, amazingly...successful launch for the first two hundred fifty milliseconds.
And, then after that things started to get less good the funny part about this particular stories I
was flying down here san-francisco to visit a customer I'm on version amer
...are the version flies around here is I've got my go-go internet and written for my facebook
...I actually see the...question the individual basically saying
hey you guys really...took my thing down and say well,
you know, I'd love to help out and make this thing better and then my link ranks and goes,
yeah, we've got an issue can help validates this was actually kind of near and dear to me so keeping this sort of
situation in mind let's actually go
through what the agency could have done without over
building rover spending a little bit along the way in order to be ready for this
...thirty thousand...ps it's quite doable with the right
...to write design and giving us the right amount money like that last part
okay so we're going to frame discussion on for axes so all of the
measure customer advise routine depth engagements we think about architecture always looking at these
four things are great way to frame the
non functional aspects of the system functional stuff is nebulous
as it is because you're working with humans and...a little fuzzy these are the for that will kill you
...conditions of success and scale scaleability being...things
can I add more resources to the system efficiently that being can I add them and kind of
...use them...them and mi using the deployed resources effectively this is
probably the single biggest change moving from a closed world enterprise system where you can literally
name every single user because there probably are global address list to
going to open world dynamic mode and growth systems where you don't know who's going to show up and if
you're wildly successful the world is going to show up physically the biggest changes
were used to capitalizing for thirty six months out I'm going to look at
my fairly structured load profile and I think how big a set of
...to buy for three years from now and I'm and advertise mechanics across them fantastic
...grossly overpaid for all the stuff I'm not using a replace them
to years anyway luckily in the cloud we have more options but unless we plan
appropriately we can add more small units of work it doesn't work out so well and some
of the inefficiencies that you can get away with in a world we have lots of actress capacity
I'll play so well when the world shows up on your door
course availability you get enough stuff everything fails.
Every single thing is going to fail under enough time enough pressure and enough
humans because humans are the leading cause of outages so who's ever fat fingered configure file update
...system down you don't put your hand-up you're probably weren't paying
attentionI've done this configuration is actually the
most dangerous thing to availability because it is the one piece of your code that has no
error handling I've seen one...two systems in my life
...didn't trust their own configuration almost everything explicitly...
configuration and it's the easiest thing that live edit on a system...talk about that when we get
the single-most important one of this list in terms of operating cloud service or I
large-scale web application experience of scale is manageability telemetry and...
do I actually know what's going on my site and can I make...the twitter is
a very effective site availability tracking mechanism...
very effective because the world will tell you you're down and you suck I would like to explore some options
...have twitter be the thing that doesn't tell you your site is down?
And, if you're doing platform development if you're building release over
release over release feasibility is the system simple enough for your dev team
...your budget to be able to keep building out new releases without
accumulating absurd amounts of technical debt because we all low-paying down technical debt when we have time
and because...have lots of that so for...make sense we have a
Going on really going to hammer on this one because even I was talking to my guys today and he
was having this discussion had actually inflated the two sides of scaleability can I
add more capacity I can go and get a thousand the m but can customers get to them and
...assuming...stateless get to their state or to the piece of state that they need
really this is all about where're the martian points where the contention where the...to be aware of
how do I add more capacity efficiently and subtle considerations especially with regards
to mobile applications requiring push notification come back another story...a second and
then the using capacity more efficiently density traditional performance tuning avoiding
common...patterns and in identifying things like unbalanced workloads the one we're
kind of talking about thus far is a publication workload
...ninety-nine reads for every right it's a bad joke in there but I can't come up with
right now so you know, I traditional see microsoft content management system the
...traditionally architected assumes one read for every right because they both hit
highly consistent database it says that all of these recall
they're not especially conditions of success where one person might
edit one file or one piece of data and then a million reads need to happen on that
do that directly against a single centralized sequel server either
...giant sequel box or a giant oggi series
or pthree or pfour I'm okay with you want to spend more money than you have to
may even encourage it a little bit but that's not today
versus going hey this is primarily read I want to spread that thing out
self-designed considerations first set of questions to go through what kind
of application service...building it all comes from here
is it a burst mode application is where everything has to happen on a single data
...point in time is it something that needs to run only nine-to-five
...can't fail between there is it something that's primarily read is...a
lot of reading right and the question I started ask now...with customers...what portion of your budget
your actual dedicated engineering budget heads time.
Tooling everything is dedicated
...the non functional service fundamentals doing a platform that number is zero you will have
...production learning moment and they are not fun there's a less polite term use for them but I
can use here today so the anybody actually had this bacon...budgets.
Couple...cool how like you guys.
Do you have taken the first-time you did one of these?
...okay so let's go in to other things we already acne
...need a couple nods to...what you're talking about
How when you get into conditions...success there are occasions where yeah,...
really did need that a lot of the balance is going to be the how do you frame the doer how do you create
the conditions for success without having to do all the work way in advance on spec and
really finding that balance between testing before production because you're let's be honest you're always
testing and production whether you want to are not just excepted really what we're talking
...making...decision of how much effort are we going to put in to fill in how much
the test space to prevent
outrageous surprises but people will still do weird things which is we come back to telemetry?
Ok, so, let's talk about a scenario this is kind of mashed up it's an
amount them like three or four different customer scenarios so let's think about building
a website within a company mobile application for tracking sports events this is actually from
an internal test service we use just for understanding various service behavior
...best practices whatnot
...have to key characteristics were have burst mode meaning
that uncertain times a day or certain daily events there's going to...a game on and
during that game everybody's going to show up and then everyone's going to leave so we have these in
this case predictable spikes calendar driven spikes.
But, we also have as a variety of at potential growth because there's some social aspect in here
...hey I'm...go.
For example, this was fantasy football because nodes and addict about that.
Or at least I'm told I will be this fall as the social...you can also get these tipping points
...to come together you can actually show up with a lot of...of success
you didn't anticipate so those are things to watch out for when you designing classes system is
...burst.
You know, if it is...if you can...
that's good or at least if you can schedule it and can you get wildly successful based on
...tipping point in your user base if these are closed world enterprise target applications
you don't actually have to worry about a lot of this stuff because you're user motions don't enabling but in this case
we're a target the hard ones because it's build and let's talk about some hard fun stuff?
Workload decomposition this is key you need to understand the flows in the system and
...relative prioritization there are more I just pulled out three interesting
ones and really what we're looking for is how stateful are they what is the span of
data they touch and it mutable or immutable works so, for example,
listing out see sequence of games it's pretty much always a read workload
your update your schedule once every now and...in fact for many sports events,
you know, the schedule six months in advance and it's not changing outside of an
...that so this is a minimal consistency requirement if it takes
minutes for the sit data updates to flow through the system that's
ok so...certain range of options we can use their the status of a
live event that's a little different...read workload it's continuous can
...updates and I don't know it really comes down to user base of
can I take a second of read consistency can take a couple of seconds it really depends anything below
a second because of network transmission times doesn't really matter all that much anyway and then status of
active-x with mobile...exactly the same as the prior one but we have push notifications
and push notifications with consistently connected sockets puts a
really interesting type of stress on a system that doesn't exist in web workloads.
Because you're testing not just how much work you can
...how many active sockets can be maintained which puts
...interesting stress on your network infrastructure and guess what no
web testing workload out there in the web test tools guess what they don't stress
sockets certain about...seven months ago got a call a
...nice calm reasoned call it a good our.
Now it really wasn't it kind of went liked so,
yeah, we just lander biggest contract we had this live event with our great little mobile application
network fantastic on my desk will heard that one and we had we went
tracking this live event and...my world melted down in five minutes but we tested this
at bigger user loads like okay so we're missing some piece of data here dig in
digg in...so you guys actually tested
was how many requests per second you could push the system on like ten network sockets
...you didn't test was what if you turned on
and million active sockets did you have enough infrastructure deployed
...that the answer is well no they didn't so because a
low fidelity test created a false sense of confidence.
And, we get to the other things that they did that were bad a little bit when we talk about manageability
so again having this list...doesn't take long to put together just what
are the keep workflows to the system how stateful are they are they read are they right whereas
...data come from...any data for a particular user or is it system-wide metadata?
Right so stage one pretty much this is where we've been told you for the
last fifteen years and for certain classes system that
works great for highly dynamic fungible adversity workloads this
...pretty terrible you...replaces with linux and lamp the physics of the same
...still very bad because we can't add a
...easily and I'm also managing is a very low layer of abstraction
...website on ornamentation the transistors...old-school that's not how we want
to do the sorts of things anymore I don't need that much control of my vm is to be successful.
We could see a lot of these in fact this is has three times as many
...three times as many services that first item I mentioned sillier article
...again let's go through the process of figuring out how do we what we have
establish...baseline where are we start with
ok so capacity it's really hard to add capacity to the system because I would need to
manually configure vm get my patch levels right get my software on
their get configured added in integrate with the load balance or I
don't watch actually course...presentation how to use the actual resource managers right now so you're obviously not watching
...making this party easy but it's still
and managing gm's and there's a lot of moving parts there the other parties are...density
so a default windows server I installation with is his
tunes to protect the server.
Very perfectly reasonable things when you expect the host multiple workloads on
...instead you're in a cloud world words dynamic
its fungible like...gm's I remove them I don't want to protective gm
...protect my investment I want every ounce of cpu I went every outs of
memory every ounce of disk because I can dedicate gm's the specific tasks because they're easy to spin up
...tear down so if you have the default settings unless you go through
and to be honest properly tuning a web workload on is to reach
its rough maximum which depending on your code is about twenty three
thousand active sockets sl per core.
So, you can do this as well as
fifteen to twenty thousand ops per second in a fully asynchronous node well
...it's about three hundred settings so you probably don't want to be in that game unless
you have to unless you're targeting systems that are doing more than hundred-thousand operations per
second you probably don't need to do that okay so
...is density how efficient is my code how efficient is may configuration and,
how well and...resources that are available?
Right I have three-b microsoft each one of them is a single point
...failure in this case everything is a single...failure I cannot survive the
loss of any single piece of this infrastructure probably not great will
make it better but the most important thing of all is knowing where we stand.
Turning the lights on...so that diagram
I showed before operational insight visibility how much do we think we really get by default.
But,...head shaking is kind...get.
Most unfortunately most the times ...escalation lands
my teams desk the first question we ask is shows your log shows your telemetry help
us understand and the answers range from we don't have any.
It log too much so we turned it off.
I know it sounds funny but if you think about it this is the way we've been
conditioned we used to have test were returned on lots of telemetry and we knew have
the system behaved and then we go to production and because we
had these capitalized very expensive scale-up workloads that was really,
really expensive to do logging so we turned often production which is a really neat way of saying
for fifteen years as an industry deluded ourselves into thinking that it was more important
know-how system behaved in test imitating production think about that or the,
yeah, we turn this thing on but we never looked at it.
Back to that web applicator that mobile application that melted down because
...of sockets they actually had live monitoring services actions case it
was new relic turned on their site.
But, no, one had ever looked at the data.
Because the dev team washear the ops timor here and they weren't talking to each other so
...wasn't this understanding that this is a cycle this has to be connected
...didn't know-how to log in the portal the...guys didn't know what code look like so when we come in going
guys what failed they looked at us single asher failed obviously because in absence of data
the plates always...fault which might make you feel better but doesn't really help in root
cause analysis and remediation so this is actually the first thing you have to
...preparing for success good news is you can write your way
...three things we have to do...we all have limited resources time people money if you have unlimited
if any of these let's talk it can be from place to work temporarily so how to prioritize
need to frame the door when you to set the stage to be able to deploy more capacity
and resources without having to change code because changing coding conditions
...success and is horrifying...bad it's very terrifying I just want to run
scripps...resources need to turn the lights on any operational visibility...
know if and actually making something better has anyone ever heard behaviors the term psychic debugging?
We see this...going well why did you change that I don't know I just wanted to change
and see if it got better okay that's not unreasonable how did you measure if
it got better we watched twitter.
In conditions of crisis in can when
everything is failing it's just a natural human reaction to scramble
unless you build the discipline of data-driven engineering up-front and you practice
...on a daily basis you won't have those patterns to fall back on when success is
just within reach and you will not bluntly have time to do
this during positions of crisis so it's always better to make the few small changes up-front
but most importantly we're going to use this data that's very easy to get on a modern cloud system
specially measure and we use the drive this to understanding of where...what engineering investment
...need to make now what engineering investment can we make later and what's the
difference because most modern...pretty complicated there's a lot of moving parts I do a lot of
...based solutions and...a simple io
...base processing system can have three to four hundred workflows.
You cannot...three hundred sophisticated workflows in a day but
...point you only need is really the only tune for five of them to be successful sweeney data.
Also how do we get out of this race of...the transistor level it
just takes time and we want to focus on business value getting features and,
not having the pager and virtual pager remembers pagers...
Cannot.
...and everyone...minute pager duty now and similar services
highly bacon makes it easy to trade money for capacity now sometimes you a lot of control sometimes
...whole the m you want to go deep but for most web applications especially the front-end it's not all
that necessary so money is almost, almost always faster expanding engineering time
...generally carries less risk a lot of times what you may do in conditions
...success is let's spend a bunch of money roll-out mort capacity gets over the hump the
...time to do the right engineering work.
And, measure how do we look at migrating re hosting application
opponents their paths equivalence how do we go semantically up the stack how do we tradeoff I
svm for web apps for may known as websites I may call entire is sari code
...but that is you can basically take your web code re hosted in a...we've already gone and
done those three hundred-plus configuration settings
...wuvn in my...a manager patterns and practices we recently released a bunch of guidance
on common performance...patterns and there was one around synchronous io and
...blown up a number of customer sites so we were doing...casting...websites and we could not
break we literally could not make this condition happen we realized is that actually
gone ahead of us and done such a great job tuning the platform we couldn't break it
in the specific way...just took a standard isv...web role thing what
a snapped in minutes so we have put a lot of work in a lot of time and energy into these paths
experiences to basically make them friendlier...share...advertise some of that learning directly to
the platform and for a web for an application like this is actually not a lot of data
...lot of readers but I don't know a lot of data so being able to get that out of a sequel server
managing everything and into address...db where I get continuous point
in time backups and...really cool new featureautomatic geo replication which we'll get to
later can really help me set the stage for a for scale.
Right so.
Used to be a you if you wanted to do insight telemetry you had to build a lot of
stuff that's expensive and it's actually in many cases hard to justifying your budget unless you're actually
building a platform where you can advertise the investment so
...entry honest I really don't care what you use app insights use new relic use
app dynamics they all have free trust try them at the end of the day it's going to come down to what is your dev
...team enjoy working with what are the ones that helped them understand behavior and
flo and actually make sense of the data and a lot of...just going
to come down individual ergonomics just put...some of the
budget is try amount but rancher way...victory.
For more sophisticated platform apps humanity...build lot-of custom stuff that's a different talk but
for most websites of this perspective this get your most of the way down the road
...need to add more later but just get going with the sorts of things
and you actually have to look at the data that you have to...as part of your daily experiences.
every single system that's ever been built mechanical hydraulic
electric software they all have a...there is some point where
you will put too much weight on the system and it will snap there are two choices you find it or
your users well one of these is less heartburn inducing.
Normally the way I recommend doing this is essentially do destructive...test.
Take system...down to the smallest resource
pool you can find one...or one instance
...asher websites and just throw enough...the system to find the point where
goes nonlinear and snaps because that will tell you how efficiently
...resources on that system that will tell you about contention points it will tell you about density
...give you some understanding the scaling...if one instance can handle
...thousand users represented before tipping over then
you can extrapolate to a certain point it's not completely linear because there's other factors
...play but it's a nice cheap quick way to find out that hey,
we actually have an internal...being used in this app domain and you take
it above ten concurrent users the whole thing tips over finance early finding cheap because they're in
...most importantly this is the data that well-informed do I need to do
...to actually even need to do any performance optimization or can just throw more money at
the problem and keep my engineers working on features and functionality or do I really need
...tackle specific performance optimizations...do it on data?
Click anything
worked area so this is an app dynamic screenshot this is actually from the
...performs optimization project again we want to use insight against a
live system to understand a low-profile if you see weirdness almost every time I've
talked to a customer and they've gone through this process and they've had a live site event they may go,
yeah, actually we saw this become months ago we just didn't know that little
hiccup that weird piece of data meant something was terribly wrong you won't have time and resources to
chase every single thing down but it's worth taking a couple of extra minutes and
...are low harness broken or like shooters actually an interesting bug in
the system and I'm going to keep coming back to telemetry has to be part of your day-to-day life if
you've rented it's cheap it's accessible you...great stuff with.
Right so we have limited resources how
do we prioritize first thing we need to understand is what are the availability points and
how we mitigate...if I have one
...failure that can take everything down you can be guaranteed that is the thing that will fail at the point we
...the most?
And, one of the scale bottlenecks
and contention points has data flow through the system and where do you have units of one
...are only three numbers I'll come back to this the three numbers are zero one and more?
...easy because there's nothing to do one is terrifying because everything ends up there and
n is a little bit more achievable so we'll go through and figure out how do we add more stuff.
Okay,
so, assuming we've already ported are site over to measure web apps I'm going to
keep going websites and sql tv what are the
...the things that are consumed so in the case of measure web apps I compute instances
I'm running the m so by default on a normal subscription I can get up to ten
and well tuned code that's a lot of but if you need more
you-can call us again it's not a technical imitation it's actually building and
...limitation and we can crank
...up we have some very large internal dedicated clusters that are available if your application demand.
The reason I keep pushing on the mobile apps is that can current active sockets web socket
connections that's a meter resources well it's not always an obvious one so
...a lot of continuously connected push base notification by signal are you have to
take that into account you have to be able to test that as well it's actually pretty hard.
Requests per second for vm really comes down to efficiency
of implementation if you have purely synchronous code
it may not be as good if you have blocking calls if you have dependencies and externally
meter resources authentication being the most common one there will be you can only
gets...doesn't matter how many of...m you add you will only get so much work through the system but there
are n web apps and there is one database
ok that's a bit of a red flag in terms of potential scaleability because I have
no way I can scale-up from a standard pone ptwo-p three before but,
that depending if I had particularly inefficient code that may not be enough common
...number of connections to given database the default asp dot net connection
...one hundred a standard sequel...gives you a hundred eighty connections so with
one-point-eigth gm's under conditions of success you've just blown out your connection
Again, not hard to fix in advance not challenging six we've identified
...load testing...terrifying...live editing configure files...website.
And, database throughput if you have particularly bad database queries that choke
our take a lock escalation that only happen every now and then they'll take
down your site during conditions of success so just
...those things are there...have a great article on the on a concert the
ad icon documentation that lists out all basically all of the meter resources
...services take
a couple hours work your way through understand what those limits are and how to add more?
Like the slows clicker ever.
Failure and availability points get bad code we'll have that code...code today and
...even open visual studio so,
come on, that's funny by and large is as a containers
designed to save you from writing particularly bad code in that
...crashes will just...back up again there
is one small exception to watch out for...and above z
whenever configured fast failure detection I don't know what I'm talking about I didn't until last week
...helping customer...and issue suddenly add-in recent versions of...essentially
a fast value protection or circuit breaker that says if you like just drop.
And, number of times in a certain period we've deem that
you are completely unhealthy and will shut you down?
That features enabled by default depending on the...you're running
in so-if you get into this continuous failure cycle you may date basically just get I...turning
itself off essentially some watch out for the bigger problem here is the single
...database if you have any transient or...during...ripple all the way back and...everything is only one
of these databases this is traditional good performance tuning efficiently using
...resources but more importantly we
...something in a second were really understand splitting that read and write workload.
Right so can we reduce or shift critical of work for differential workloads
mostly around playing consistency games if I have...million people that I need to basically
update sport event or kind of the latest score.
Going to sequel on a single role selected every single time is
probably not the most efficiently I could do that I've seen a lot of sites that do this
now again you may not want to invest in things like...
up-front you probably do by the way but you might not.
Here one of the things to watch out for
...heavy structure your code in such a way that you can add these things later we have a bunch of
sabre api controllers that have direct ado dot net calls
...within them there's really nowhere to mediate you can't go in shin in
...if you have repository patterning
...have a place you can hide that it's a little bit less risky.
About two or three years ago we got a call very panicked hey we're going live
in twenty four hours for a governmental app that's tracking you know,
basically a and live event the next day and
the system tips over past thirty users like okay interesting
I felt bad for you are you doing and every single time someone log
...the site they would hit...fourteen times and
...page it worked great on my box...testing was left to
late and all of a sudden we had an overnight binge of essentially rewriting the code base
to add...not my most fun evening especially since we didn't have a lot of time for adequate testing.
The so the really difference between...this kind of approach and something I'll talk about
is this requires engineering time this requires code change this
carries higher-risk and more latency...just going to take more time to do it so you never want to
be adding caching all these other types of rippling changes to a
live production site is a badge of honor sure we've all got
the scars but you probably don't want to do it twice.
So, what
...caching like anything else it's not a magical solution in fact in some cases a
...create three problems for everyone solves however we've already done
...workload analysis we know this is a primary read workload with
low consistency requirements ok,
then now sure I can cash absolutely in adder
...fantastic easy to add good semantic support very scalable and...what I've done
is I've taken my not overly scalable on...single-point of state and
then I've tradeoff consistency and spread it out to a bunch of resonance?
But, this doesn't necessarily give me a distributed solution because in
the something like this I'm still hitting the same key the same partition the same set of data inside
...so I may employer multi-layered caching solution,
for example, if I've structured my code correctly I can turn on a
...net output cashing or even ins output caching on the rest calls that
...sports scores if I designed it that way from the beginning and then I can basically have
multi-layered of...truly have that state stored in a couple different places
...not magical just like a just another tool in the box
...can be a very useful and how do we figure out...worked ab?
Testing
with telemetry turn it on it was some load see if you basically progressed or
advanced again this is from some of the performance optimization stuffy...and get help.
Right so we actually see to the
...percentile the same set of issues around density happening again and
again and again...io is probably the worst here...systems
the target multiple databases are perhaps the worst offenders because when you say I'm database
agnostic what you're really saying is I'm the lowest common denominator between all of these databases
and take advantage of none of their features to make them run faster even we don't like to admit that but
that's largely what you see a or the other one that pictures a lot
of chatty io is blind faith in rms.
Okay, you guys been there, you know,...top of that.
Or my absolute favorite the difference between I innumerable and I query
Okay, if you...for those of you are familiar I query...means take my question...to the other
side get back just the answer I innumerable says give me every answer and then let me pick.
Common point your
test system has five rows in the metadata table your production system has a million.
...see what happens there that's the basic another example is extraneous fetching,
fetching the whole database and filtering client-side it doesn't show up until
you load test.
No, caching synchronous io we've got a full list itself on the hub and if you want a
lot more detail on...interesting...tomorrow eleven thirty am
...one-b going through eight or nine of these in a lot more detail and I don't want to sales
...because then you get mad at me so what is move on to talk about the how do we add more capacity.
All right so if you have high-fidelity
low testing usual instigated figure out doing the optimized where do we need
to optimized how far do we need to go to the thing to watch out for here the
...pattern the regression is if you're load profiles
are not based on real user data or good understanding of real user data
election tell yourself lives like are my friends who had the mobile app they
had great...test numbers...that everything was fantastic except for the
load test wasn't actually testing system resources...you know,
of a real...real use in a real site
easiest way to do this especially if you're if you have a couple of really users...already have a
...production just look at the telemetry model
...workflows and pull that back in the load testing.
Also...these things don't try to optimize everything and actually...day most of
it doesn't matter observe measure change react.
Go make sure you can basically say on this build this version we got this much
load for this many resources we made this change we got better we got worse and moved on.
Most the time and the systems I've seen if you only hit two or three the primary workflows
through the system all the way down all the way back up again you generally hit your business goals
going in and just doing this global optimization exercises without targeted data
...you end up spinning in circles and spending a lot of time and effort.
So, mapping the third stage of journey we've talked a lot about
it's fairly high-level detail but again this is paternal session about the questions and
decision matrix...the journey
for getting to a good single datacenter solution but.
...for global we have customers all over the world more we could have customers all of the world
...think about multiple datacenters within I think that redundancy how do we go from
our now truly awesome one datacenter solution to multiple datasets this
is been on.
A big thing for a long-time who's sever set up kind of database replication across
datacenters couple...funner want.
Course like no that was terrible and ...traditionally setting up all the hardware
in the physics and the...over in order to be able to actually
...multiple datacenters for business continuity disaster recovery or even...
global scale reasons is very challenging nine eleven demo because I don't believe in
...things in architecture sessions...talk about a path and a process that you can use
to basically go from now I've got my one datacenter how do I start adding others but more importantly why
does each step along the way work I didn't highlighted this...the beginning but,
you guys of course free to ask questions at any time
I got to forty minutes before I mention that I forgot to give myself a little bit of a break but
...jumps on a microphone I'll just keep going if you do depending a question I keep going anyway.
It's just...
So, again,
there are only three numbers zero one and lots.
And, lots of spelled and but it's still lots.
Of ultimately as long as we have the ability to use and resources
...any piece of our system we can now we're now ready to simply tell the platform give
me more of this thing and my system will know how to take care of it using one storage account...easy
...storage accounts is substantially harder going from to storage accounts
...accounts is usually really, really simple of course in the case of storage I guess
...data lake discussion earlier announcement.
...going to keynote.
Enough falsely.
So, one of things we announced earlier and again there's an enormous amount of information there so I owen expect all the
...all in the you guys...time to...to be honest I need some time the digest that are
...halfway announced we're just getting to...build and stuff.
So, one of the new services the aggregate...has been she says, you know,
this whole composing multiple storage accounts for scale it's hard when we just make
that easy for you will give you the illusion the facade...as you can reach out and
...of will do all the magical work behind-the-scenes of composing all these storage accounts and
we'll just give you one head...so
...specific case going from one storage account for data manipulation to
n storage accounts is you can do-it-yourself or you can use...service we're looking at
enabling that across broader pieces the platform but we're not quite there yet for everything so you just need
to you need to account for a little bit for working with databases if you actually have a
lot of data then things like elastic scale will really help there that's a way to go
from one to n but in the case of the scenario working through it won't help
because there's not that much data it's almost all metadata anyway and the problem really is publishing
it not changing on-the-fly...three things we need to think about in
this specific case each with their own set of resources their own state management and their
own sanitize asia in terms of how do you find it how do you use it...the front-end
...web resources is
...low state all I really need to do is get code replicated on
a continuous basis to...datacenters there's a little caveat there and
...caveat might be about having automatic level replication updates.
It also means automatic level replication mistakes.
And, I'm actually very serious here in that and one of the things to watch out for when you have
...doing these continuous update cycles is if you see you will there will be
...bugs...be mistakes will be errors and essentially if you set up the
ability to automatically role stuff...production of the world.
That means that you've now...that mistake is not isolated one place...test environment is now everywhere
...clot back back-end database highly stateful and
...in this specific workload I need some form of eventually consistent data replication I need
a way to basically have that data be local to a number of other datacenters either in the
cache there or in actual database
there and I need to be able to take users and spread them across all of these front-ends.
It's actually not that bad it's a little details the game...just kinda go through
...adventure here now and meander through some stuff we can do so let's start from
are barely visible sorry about that one datacenter deployment so we've got
...websites we've got a number of production instances and
we are using the staging capability of asher websites to put our changes
are new stuff in special staging environment so we can ensure that
its functional before we flip the bit over as an atomic operation we have
...database with this suddenly named...we'll get to
that a second as well as a...cash...we've decided that we need caching here.
Key state starting point is I need to be able to stand one of these up through automation I can't be in
the portal clicking on things it's great for exploring it's wonderful for dev task but the harsh
realities by the time you're looking at doing global datacenter operations you must be
...fully automated state good news is with the release of the
...manager stuff this can be deterministic operation we say this is what my environment
looks like please deploy one of these...getting out of the world of imperative programming
be it you know, our...she alive into the world of this is my environment please
...me one but you need to make the up-front investment so that when it comes time to push
out the update its run a script not get...five people doing they had this chicken
...going can you email me the updates like...check them in and do the build...my machine?
I have an abortion work with customers for whom email was their source code control system.
And, there's two sides I want to go it's twenty fifteen get is awesome
but the other time I realized under extreme pressure we fall back
on the obvious and not always optimal...you need to make these we need to
make these changes in advance so that the easy path is the right one because we're so used to doing...
So, first thing we're going to do is we're going to get automated publishing setup so websites
...is really great get integration feature so...push...build I can get an automatic build
and then deployment to staging which I can then manually promote after doing
...testing or operational snow testing again automated global deployment creates learning
moments...learning moments especially not in production
...great feature works nicely and it's
...not it's a really great integrated aspect...challenges this only works if you also
have a good branching structure where you have clean our eyes and
f flies into basically the thing that goes out in a product so you need a little bit
more up-front investment in your...process but ...like ll folks using get.
All right you got your hands...folks we're going to try out get everyone else in the room.
Actually you whether you centralized version control like...or use decentralized like it really
is a matter of culture and preference as long as you're using one using a properly so as long as get good branch
...everyone knows this is how my changes go from a feature branch or developer branch
...into staging and then
...to the kind of the test site in good shape.
Second thing we idea is we're going to make sure there are telemetry services
are enabled and they are flowing data here's one of the
gotcha to watch out for depend when you set up app insights...new relic
...dynamics or whatever you choose to use you need the way to basically name
at the deployment and they all do it slightly differently and the reason is in
production I have version one of pride in staging I have one-point-one
...unless there's a unique identifier that basically identifies topology you're sitting down looking at
the dashboard blended data you have no idea
...this the new one is the old one is...good is it bad so again that little bit of
up-front work in terms of cure my...here
is the version associated with them here is basically the unique stamp so
I can go back to my source code repository and creek create that goldin build.
Because if I need that if I'm...role this out...different data sets and everything is ready is to
basic gets ready to go from one to n and r operations and the
...staff who really should talk to each other from time to time
than helpful they must be comfortable working with that data they must be able to slice and dice
through and use this is part of their daily exerciser going was
...good built do the right things did we have regression is it on.
All really good things.
Right so we now have what we considered a pretty good one dc solution.
All right so first thing we're going to do is we're going to stand-up as
your traffic manager to set the stage...deployments
...still just going to have one datacenter but we're going to front-end it with asher traffic manager with the appropriate
...changes that basically says someone comes to you and you're going
to resolve to the cone.
Not make any other changes quite yet knowing test that make sure everything's fine.
Again, it's all about iteratively setting the stage.
...the ability to go back any point if you make mistakes.
So, next thing we roll-out the additional datacenters
again script change the topology push that we connect these other
datacenters to get publishing as well so they...continuous feed of updates we don't put them on
the measure traffic manager quite yet because they don't have any data.
Ok, so, far so good and the title on the slide is wrongly should actually be global
role output I added this earlier today don't tell anyone.
So, the...latin almost the last piece...to do here is we're going to use a really,
really cool new feature a relatively now.
In as...sequel db...geo replication and we're going to do is
...say hey dc...is my primary I'm
...basically you backing system is your responsibility to
continuously replicate the changes I make my primary to all of my secondary snout if I want
to secondary staff secondary is to be readable I need to use
...but the point which I'm ready to do this wonderful global
deployment I'm ready to step up and I'm ready to put more resources into the system and premium gives me a
way to trade money for engineering resources in time...you do not want to build this
yourself it's just carries a lot of risk.
So, the point as I have the continuous data replication flowing I now
have my code which is automatically rolling out...staging across all my
data centers I have measure traffic manager routing my data appropriately I
have my data being replicated so each one of these I can hit.
There were two caveats here most of the ...about easily
...your way to victory most of the monitoring solutions but they don't do is give you
a global roll up the say that these five applications are actually one big service you may have to
invest an additional tooling in order to build that single-point dashboard or you
by for monitors and you put them side-by-side.
I'm not kidding I've actually seen that...number of times because it was quick and only required a trip down
to best buy to buy time to do it right.
Constance...
And, then we turn on the other things...traffic manager...we put our feet up and go
okay we're now actually in pretty good shape so come full circle back to
story at the beginning this was not exactly how that remediation unfolded.
How it actually unfolded...time pressure scramble communication
paths was in a five-and-a-half our period some wonderful folks from
css and dx sat down crunches...website and
figured okay we can basically get this optimal enough
to put into three datacenters all pointing at the same sequel database with
...asp that output
...installed to survive tobias about two weeks?
So,...five-and-a-half hours to get back life and then in those two weeks they
...re factored all of the data storage layer in order to take advantage of real
...reticent optimism queries.
But, again, that was a five-and-a-half our downtime during a critical media event they
could have been avoid the actual real meadow
the story there is a lot of folks use digital marketing agencies and digital media agencies.
Okay,...I can get really candid.
Different kinds of software different I.
I I've spent ten years doing mobile...doing imbedded development and good
...until about the last ten years doing large-scale distributed
systems gotten pretty good that because I made a lot of mistakes if you put mediacy mediad...a
...am a mobile application if you get a stick figure
you're doing well because it's a different type of app make different choices
are a lot of agencies and system integrator that are very good at they
have core competency I've had and for escalation in the last couple years from the same root
...a team which phenomenally amazingly
good doing mobile apps and digital experiences but who has never built a
scalable back in system they get chosen and then they have learning
moments so if you're either in the position building such a team where
...hiring such a team make sure there's a balance
skillset because you don't want someone learning about all of this stuff and you're...
All right.
So, this is turning on...as
...sequel db geo replication I don't often come up and
say that's something that is like a really hard physics...engineering problem we've
made absurdly simple but in this case we really did you go in you pick
a gr replication you see which other datacenters you
...replicated to stand-up some new databases and if you're in premium mode
...the readable it actually works really well.
All right so if you...that feature highly recommended all
right quick recap...about the six-and-a-half minutes we have left
...together before I throw it open some questions for warning in advance
...don't ask me questions I will ask you questions mine will be more awkward
so most of the changes I've talked about they did not
involve changing code changing code at the last-minute is risky
it's dangerous and under stress and strain people will make mistakes so
let's avoid that let's use these techniques in terms of having a dynamic
cloud environment to build add more capacity the system to by the time to do the code
right based on data and observation we need to grow and go quickly
...a good thing not to have to write code it's a good thing just
...sinus small dynamic check.
But, unless you have a strong foundation to build on unless you invested in observation
...telemetry by renting it not building
it you won't know if you're up down moving for moving
...moving sideways you need to have a system architected to allow you to
add more capacity and add more resources any to pay attention to where the
single-point of failure and work around them adding all the capacity front-end capacity in the
world will not save you from creating too many connections are creating a
...escalation...everything rippling back from that you have to watch out...single-point
...but ultimately the biggest thing is if you're if you're making data-driven decisions
if you an easy way to look...system...stick some people called load testing
...a more colloquial term nc system response and make decisions there
you're in a much better situation especially in moments of stressing crisis to know that
mi making decisions that are...the world better and you will make some that make
it worse but you'll and be able to immediately go wow that just took us from like a hundred ops
...three we should probably back that change out and because we invested mail-in
it's just backing feature branch out and because we try doing that we had as part of
our culture beforehand...our day-to-day experiences we weren't name looking up
the get manual while the site was down because that's never happened
they totally did that all right so thanks for...pontificate for fifty
six minutes so the mikes are now open actually one quick little thing I
...much like successes exhilarating terrifying its most awesome thing they can ever happen
...building software is also terrifying if you weren't quite ready for it to be honest a lot of times
...never actually quite ready...to get the foundations right up-front
inside this life if the lights aren't on you are stumbling around the dark...telemetry and look at
it and spend your way to victory engineering time is too expensive it's best to do that in a
call measured fashion my team has a clinic and up on the third-floor will be here all week
...you have design questions your scenarios you have interesting things you want to do...just want to come make fun of
...by all means to get a great bunch of folks with a libm lot-of wipe words and we're happy to nerd with you.
Right so.
Site to questions so the first one is in the geo replicated
sequel database and scenario how to write to secondary datacenters fullback the
primary I was one of some is going to catch that one and the second question has to do how does
it with failures...primary so I'll take them in order to the first question is
...you kind of left out the part where you only had
one readable primary how does that happen so there's two ways to handle this
...one is you allow mutate...mute data mutation
...from any deployed instance but in your code you actually have to
connection strengths one is this is where I go to read data another one is this is
...again you or you say I can only do
rights on the primary datacenter or the third one which is
a significantly more engineering investment which is you implement command query response segregation
ascension use message driven updates but that's a lot of work.
So, the second one is around what happens if that primary database itself fails over you
to options you can di which is the easy thing to do or
what you can do is put the system any reduced response state saying that right workloads
are temporarily offline and then just continue to read from
cash or if you want to add engineering investment start reaching out across the network
the other secondary datacenters again it's just how far down that click
stop of engineering investment you want to go where's the
...no right answer what's wrong answers but no one truly right answer?
That's great that's helping...pick up on that.
I'll time for one more...I'm going to ask one.
...rate...if you...if design questions you just want to walk through scenarios you in a kind of just
...some stuff we are all were so we ran for the
rest week or more than happy to go into any many detail highly recommend check out the stuff we have on
...hub lots of...detail there we love pr as we love issues
...love discussion and other than that I hope you guys...conference and I have...